[Music]
tango refers to the source of
everything in the universe and the
universal law
in which everything continuously goes
through cycles
of creation and destruction phoomse
symbolizes the root principle of
universal philosophy
and is constructed by applying the truth
inherent in teguc's
yin and yang principles teguk ildja
stands for gun of the eight trigrams
and symbolizes the sky which embodies
the concept of birth and beginnings
and the root of all things poomsae teguc
is the first thing you learn when you
begin your taekwondo training
it is designed for the exertion of only
a little force
even beginners not used to these moves
will be able to master it
teguk iljang also includes methods on
how to complete movements
and to change direction by stepping or
turning around the pumseh progress line
we will now take a look at the pumseh of
teguk iljang
consists of nine key moves namely kibon
jumbi jase
aremaki jirigi
anmaki uyomaki
these are the basics to the nine key
moves of teguk iljang
we will now take a closer look at each
of the key moves of teguk ilchang
kibon jumbi begins with moasaki
where you can stand and move your left
foot about a foot's length to your left
breathe in open your fists and raise
them from the lower abdomen
up to the solar plexus
breathe out then lower your fists back
to the lower abdomen
your face torso and lower body should be
balanced along the center line
and your weight should be placed evenly
on both feet
both elbows should be bent like the
internal angles of a hexagram
and your fists should be placed apart
about a fist's length
retain 30 of your breath in the lower
abdomen
once the preparatory move is complete
and be careful not to raise or tense
your shoulders
areemaki is a technique used to block an
opponent's attack
towards the lower body with your outer
wrist
the blocking arms elbow should be
straightened in a way that positions
your fist
above your knees about two fists length
and the wrist on the supporting arm
should be straightened so that the back
of your hand faces down
and the wrist touches above the waist
the torso and arm should spin
simultaneously
and the blocking arms elbow should not
move in a straight line
jiriki jittigy is a technique used to
attack an opponent's
torso by thrusting with the fist the
thrusting arm should be straightened
and your fist should form a straight
line with the target's philtrum
solar plexus lower abdomen etc
the wrist of your supporting arm should
be straightened so that the back of your
hand faces down
and the wrist touches above the waist
the thrusting arm should move straight
forward slightly brushing the waist
your elbow should not open outwards and
the supporting arm should be pulled back
slightly brushing your waist as well the
supporting arm should not be pulled back
excessively pulling the shoulder along
with it
the spin of the thrusting wrist should
complete once your fist makes contact
with the target
it is important to keep a straight line
when punching a target with your fist
unlucky is a technique used to defend
from an opponent's outside attack
using the outer wrist the outer wrist
should be level with the solar plexus
and the location of your fist
should coincide with the central line
when initiating the move
the hand of your supporting arm should
be slightly straightened at the level
of the solar plexus and the hand of the
defending arm should protect
inwardly the beginning position is about
a fist's length above the shoulder
the elbow of your defending arm should
defend by pulling towards the torso and
the elbow of the supporting arm should
be pulled slightly
brushing your waist at the same time
oryomaki
is a technique used to protect from an
opponent's attack
towards the face by raising your outer
wrist cross your arms in front of your
solar plexus
and protect from an opponent's attack by
raising them upwards
the fist on the defending arm should be
above the elbow
the arm should be tilted with a space
about the size of a fist
between the back of the wrist and the
forehead
be careful not to raise your arm
excessively
leaving space between the head and arms
when seen from the front
up tuggy is a technique used to kick
towards a front target
in a straight line the kick should be
made with your leg bent
so that the kicking leg starts on top of
the knee of your supporting leg
the forward kicking leg should be bent
in a way where your front sole touches
the ground first
and your breathing and moves should
complete when your rear sole
touches the ground train this technique
using coordination of the upper and
lower body
naranjisoki consists of keeping your
feet parallel so that the back of the
foot blades face each other
straightening your knees and stand
naturally as if stopping after walking
the center of your body should be placed
in between your feet
the chest relaxed the distance between
your feet
for obsole is about one step the center
of your body should be placed between
your feet
and your body should stand straight the
back of the foot blade on the front foot
and the inner part of the heel on the
hind foot should be on the same line
and the sole of the hind foot should
face outwards with a tilt of around 30
degrees
apgubi is a standing posture where the
knee on the front leg is bent
and the two legs are spread apart front
to back
the distance between the front and hind
foot should be about one and a half
steps
and the space between the two feet
should be about the length of a fist
the knee and foot of the front leg
should face forward
and the sole of the hind foot should
face outwards with a tilt of around 30
degrees
the knee of your front leg should not
bend excessively nor should it be
sticking out in front of the tip
of the foot your hind leg should
straighten in a straight line
these are the basics to the nine key
moves of teguk
iljang we will now look at the nine
moves in succession
connecting each move the key moves of
teg-il-chang
first part consist of when are maki
shift your weight to the sole of your
right foot
move your left foot lightly
brushing the ground so the soul of the
left foot touches the ground before the
other
your breathing should be identical to
that of maki
the movement your rear soul touches the
ground completing the move
nediki should be performed softly
naturally with two knees
backward doradiki from oren apsugi
orangirigi should be performed with your
weight on the sole of the left foot
the heel of the right foot should not be
above the ground when performing
when abkhubi nerumaki
cautions for tegug-iljang first part
taking a closer look
when performing jiriki be careful not to
pull back the shoulder of the supporting
arm
when performing nediki be careful not to
let the rear sole
touch the ground first when performing
arimaki
be careful not to bend your elbows
excessively
and naturally connect to jiriki
we will now practice the moves of tegu
jiang
first part in succession slowly while
watching the video
second part consists of
and when when connecting to oren apsogi
and wen amaki from the previous move
push on the ground with your right foot
and shift your weight to the left foot
then perform by pulling your right foot
then when performing the ben opsogee and
set your feet and release the tension in
the defending arm
and connect to jiriki it is important to
maintain equal tension
on both arms when performing judigi and
refrain from exerting unnecessary force
then place weight on the sole of the
right foot turn and set
move your left arm facing the direction
of progress
and perform the preparatory anmaki move
with your right arm
complete on maki the moment the rear
sole of the left foot
touches the ground cautions for
tegeljang
second part taking a closer look
when performing oren apsogi when on maki
do not put your feet together and
perform wen apsuki
and wen anmaki
your elbow should not move away from the
body when performing on maki
this is in order to properly transfer
the energy from the spinning of the
torso to the arm
we will now practice the moves of
tegukirjang
second part in succession slowly while
watching the video
the key moves of teguc third part
consist of wen olgurmaki oren aptagi
and oren jiriki oren or gulmaki
wen aptagi anwen jirigi
when performing protect the face by
crossing your defending arm from under
your supporting arm
the fist on the defending arm should be
raised first
then move your hand slightly up to face
level and defend by snapping the elbow
up
your other fist should be pulled to the
waist and aligned with the center line
of the wrist protecting the face
the space between the back of the wrist
of the defending arm and forehead
should be about the size of a fist and
the elbow above the fist
should be tilted downwards
cautions for tegrug iljiang third part
taking a closer look be careful not to
let the elbow of the defending arm
fall back we will now practice the moves
of
tedguk iljang third part in succession
slowly
while watching the video
the key moves of tegukirjang fourth part
consist
of wen aremaki and orangirigi
push on the ground following the
previous move
place weight on the right foot turn and
set your left foot
90 degrees inwardly
perform the wen akubi and when aramaki
set your foot for apgubi sogi and shout
with orenjurgi
simultaneously
place weight on the right foot turn and
set
borrow
cautions for tegrug iljah fourth part
taking a closer look
when setting your foot from apgu sogi to
the next
apgubisogi be careful not to let your
height change
also be careful not to perform multiple
moves
when turning to borrow
we will now practice the moves of teghuk
iljang fourth part in succession
slowly while watching the video
this concludes training for tegu giljang
we will take another look at all the
moves and master
pumseh
we have looked at the key moves of
tegukirjan and provided
thorough explanations for each move and
things to watch out for
as a new initiate in the art of
taekwondo
we urge you to maintain your passion
until the end
continuously and repeatedly honing your
skills
we'll see you again in the teguk ijang
video
thanks for watching